<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Tiffany&#39;s Webpage</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Tiffany&#39;s Webpage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Switching to Linux From Windows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/linuxnoob/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/linuxnoob/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;random stuff about my computer and linux noob experience&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Previously, my desktop computer had Windows 10 installed for a while. I mainly used it only for watching media and playing video games. Then I updated to Windows 11 in order to get system/security updates, but I only used it for a month. The ui was extremely bloated, with random news/copliot/weather icons on the lock screen, desktop screen, menu, taskbar, basically everywhere. For Windows in general I found the Windows filesystem/commandprompt/powershell confusing to use, and files that should be saved to documents would save to onedrive for some reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>random stuff about my computer and linux noob experience</p>
<p>Previously, my desktop computer had Windows 10 installed for a while. I mainly used it only for watching media and playing video games. Then I updated to Windows 11 in order to get system/security updates, but I only used it for a month. The ui was extremely bloated, with random news/copliot/weather icons on the lock screen, desktop screen, menu, taskbar, basically everywhere. For Windows in general I found the Windows filesystem/commandprompt/powershell confusing to use, and files that should be saved to documents would save to onedrive for some reason.</p>
<p>So I decided recently during this month (November 2025) to switch to using Linux Mint. I figured out how to do some basic customization with the default and downloadable applets, extensions and themes. I added the OrchideaDock theme from the download section. On my taskbar I added switcher and windows quick list, which are convenient for managing different windows and seeing what I have opened. For extensions, I downloaded Negate Window Super+I which lets me invert any window I recently clicked on, and gTile where I can tile my windows without struggle.</p>
<p>Desktop
<img src="/images/desktop.png" alt="image1"></p>
<p>Downloading files on Linux Mint wasn&rsquo;t too difficult as long as the software I wanted had clear documentation, and worked for Debian or Ubuntu. The software manager is super easy to download from and there is a lot of popular applications avaiable, like Steam and VLC Player. I tried out new apps I have never used before, like RSS Guard which lets me save a feed of things I want to follow without having to manually check different websites or channels, and SuperTuxKart which is like a less bloated Mario Kart.</p>
<p>I was able to run Bloons Tower Defense 6, Counter-Strike 2, Team Fortress 2, and Minecraft Java Edition on my system natively or with steam proton. Protondb.com shows reports on what games work or doesn&rsquo;t work on Proton. I&rsquo;m not going to try to test what other games will work on my system though. I&rsquo;m going to use this as a opportunity to stop buying new ones on steam or any game market.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
